要怎么做
So how is this supposed to work?
你我相对而坐  谈心聊天
You sit. I sit. We talk.
-谈什么  -想谈什么都行
- About what? -About whatever you want.
你想听我抱怨我老妈吗
You want me to whine about my mother?
你想抱怨你老妈吗
Do you want to whine about your mother?
我可以跟你说我五岁时我的金鱼死了的事
I can tell you about the time I was five and my goldfish died.
如果你想从那开始
If that's where you'd like to start.
我生命中的经历数不胜数
I've had a billion things happen to me in my life.
我怎么知道那件事是有关系的
How am I supposed to know which ones are relevant?
依我看来  所有的事都是有联系的
As far as I'm concerned, they're all relevant.
好吧  那么我们最好快点
Well, we better get moving,
不然得花五十年听我叨叨
Cause this session could take 50 years.
没错  你是所有经历的集合
Yes, you are the sum of everything that's happened to you
的确如此  有些经历影响更深远
And, yes, some events are more relevant than others.
可是  唯一能找出关键经历的方法
But, uh, the only way we can figure out which ones are
就是聊天
Is to talk.
告诉我吧
So tell me,
你在想什么
What's on your mind?
你想要什么
What do you want?
我想好起来
I want to get better...
不管是什么意思
Whatever the hell that means.
我厌恶苦不堪言的生活
I'm sick of being miserable.
所以你想快乐起来
So you'd like to be happy?
不用想也知道  没错  我要快乐
Again with the reflecting yes, I'd like to be happy.
快乐是个很棒的目标
Being happy is an excellent goal.
很多病人甚至不知道
Not many patients can crystallize
自己想要摆脱什么
Exactly what they're hoping to get out of this.
我好怕哦
Well, bully for me.
所以现在所要做的就是
So now all we have to do
找出怎么让你从这此找到快乐
Is figure out how to get you from here to happy.
抗抑郁药吗
Ssris?
这就是你的天才办法吗
That's your genius technique?
我们不该放弃任何有帮助的方式
I don't think we should ignore any tools that can help.
我知道你不怕吃药
I know you don't have a problem taking drugs.
那是因为我的腿疼
For my leg, for pain.
那就当作这是治精神疼痛的药
Well, think of this as being for psychic pain.
我不想改变自己
I don't want to change who I am.
你痛苦吗
Miserable?
你觉得药物会抹去你的过人之处
Do you think that by taking meds you'll lose your edge,
再也没有让你如此出色的独到见解
Stop making the unique connections that make you a successful doctor?
如果梵高是你的病人
If Van Gogh was your patient,
他就想要刷房子
He'd be satisfied painting houses
而不是画出传世佳作《繁星夜晚》
Instead of the "Starry Night".
梵高
Van Gogh
仍然会画出让世人赞叹的夜空
Would still be making inspired paintings of the night sky,
只是不会在收容所里
Just maybe not from the room of his asylum.
-这你可说不准  -我就知道
- You don't know that. - I know
他的耳朵会完好无缺
Both his ears would be intact.
还有他的生活会好很多
And I know his life would be better.
我知道这对你来说不容易
I know this doesn't come naturally to you.
可你需要我的帮助
But you want my help,
你就要信任我
Which means you need to trust me.
好吃
Delicious.
你怎么在这里
Why are you here?
我在等上帝赐食
I'm waiting for my communion wafer.
你没有咽下去  对吧
You're cheeking it, right?
没
Nope.
跟我说你是装的
Tell me you're cheeking it.
我咽下去了
I swallowed it.
怎么会  我们不吃药的
No, you didn't. We don't take meds.
是你不吃药  阿瓦  我可想保持头脑清醒
You don't take meds, Alvie. I decided to get sane.
你在耍花招的  快说啊
You're scamming again. You can tell me.
没什么花招  阿瓦
I'm not scamming, Alvie.
他们打败了你
They broke you.
他们没有打败我
They didn't break me.
我早已一败涂地了
I am broken.
别再把我当偶像了
Now stop worshipping me
好好想想你的悲惨人生吧
And go and worry about your own loser life.
我恨你
I hate you.
舞会吗
Prom?
给你一个任务
Got an assignment for you.
角色扮演
Role-playing?
我可不觉得装成个恋脚癖的商人有什么用
I'm not sure how pretending to be a businessman with a foot fetish is gonna help,
可是我奉陪到底
But I'm game.
你和其他病人有紧密联系吗
Have you connected with any of the other patients?
已经来这里四周了
You've been here four weeks.
说说和其他病人处的怎么样
Tell me about your relationships with the other patients.
黛安
Diane...
觉得沉默女讨厌她
Is convinced that silent girl hates her.
里克特没有你想得那么偏执
Richter's not as paranoid as you think.
可他喜欢让你们这么想
He just likes that you think that.
还有我的室友恨我
And my roommate hates me.
只有一件事
Only one of the things you said
提到别人对你的感觉
Indicated how somebody else feels about you.
这么说
So...
我相信仅靠初步分析
I'm sure that they've done some form
他们就可以得出"我是混蛋"的结论
Of rudimentary analysis on me, concluded that I'm a jerk.
有办法能消除他们的成见
You know, there is a way for them to find out things about you
不用逻辑推理吗
Without deductive reasoning.
我能处理好人际关系
I have had relationships.
你总毁掉人际关系  会伤害身边的每一个人
You've screwed up relationships, every one of them
甚至像是有意而为
Almost like that was the goal.
我希望你
I want you
信任
To trust...
别人
People.
试试吧
Try.
穿戴好
Get dressed.
只要敞开心扉吗
Just open up?
没错  敞开心扉
Just open up.
学着信任
Trust.
从陌生人开始吗
Strangers?
一般是先从陌生人开始
We'll start with strangers,
循序渐进
Then work our way up.
如果过火了
If it helps,
我就用"你好"来帮你打圆场
I find "hello" to be an excellent icebreaker.
嗨
Hi.
像是"你好"的简化版
It's like "hello," only shorter.
是啊
Yes.
能省点时间是件好事
I'm glad we were able to save that time.
您衣着光鲜  应该是捐赠人吧
Judging by the fancy suit, I'd say you were a donor.
您坐立不安  遇到烦心事了吗
The nervous demeanor says maybe you've had issues,
可能这地方对你来说有特殊意义
Probably is why this place has personal meaning.
其实是我闹心
But this is supposed to be about me.
我利用了我的朋友
I take advantage of my friends.
真的只是朋友
Friend, really
我就那么一个
I've only got one.
有时是挺艰苦
It can be tough sometimes.
我可不是同性恋
I'm not gay.
我也不是
Oh, neither am I.
实际上  我是的
Actually, I am.
看到那边那位帅哥吗
See that guy over there?
我的爱人
He's my lover.
还是我的心理医生
He's also my psychiatrist,
有人说这不合适
Which some would argue is a little inappropriate,
那是他们不懂爱
But they just don't know what love is.
您觉得呢
Am I right?
你才不是同性恋
You're not gay.
当然不是  可我被逼跟别人分享小秘密
No, but I have to tell intimate secrets to people.
也许你真该是同性恋
Maybe they should be true.
我还真没想到这一点
Hadn't thought of that.
安全起见  还是做双性恋吧
To be on the safe side, I should probably do both,
先玩好玩的
Starting with the fun ones.
来吧  快乐升级
Come on, let's get me better.
我是多情浪子
I'm a philanderer.
是吗
Oh.
四处留情并不意味着我是个慈善家
Philanderer doesn't mean that I give a lot to charity.
-就是  -我知道是什么意思
- It means... - I know what it means.
你刚才问我
Uh, you were asking me
点心里有没有坚果
If there were any nuts in the hors d'oeuvres.
什么
What?
亲爱的
Honey.
我丈夫刚才跟你说什么了
What did my husband just say to you?
我
I...
问他点心里
Was asking him if there were nuts...
有没有坚果
In the hors d'oeuvres.
那你的肾上腺素呢[过敏药]
Then where is your epipen?
什么
My what?
有过敏史的人都应该带着的
No one with an allergy would walk around without an epipen.
-钱包我看看  -不要
- Give me your purse. - No.
-把钱包给我  -停手
- Give me your purse. - Stop!
-给我  -不要
- Come. - No.
到底怎么回事
What really happened
是
Is...
我是觉得他挺帅的
I thought he was cute.
对他有点意思
I hit on him.
咱们走
We're going.
玩得怎么样
You having fun?
我确实和一个人很亲密
I did connect with one guy.
但我的顽劣本性占了上风
But then my propensity for screwing things up overtook me.
然后我爱玩的欲望又打败我的本性
Then my desire to have fun overcame my propensity.
你没搞砸啊
You didn't screw it up.
来这里不是让你真心真意地
The assignment wasn't to get you to trust people
去相信这里的人
With a piece of your soul.
而是让你知道你可以信任别人
The assignment was to teach you that you can trust.
在座的这些人有出卖你吗
Did any of these people rat you out
因为把你当作好色鬼
As the obnoxious womanizer
还是什么情色小说家
Or the porn producer that they think you are?
你为什么觉得
Why do you think
如果别人知道真相就会不好好待你呢
That people would treat you worse if they knew the truth?
晚上好  医生
Good night, doctor.
你闯祸了吗
Are you in trouble?
当然没有
Apparently not.
那下一步呢
So what's next?
想当皮条客吗
You want to be my pimp?
我们聊天好吗
Why don't we just talk?
好吧
Okay.
你怎么不气我偷你的车
How come you weren't pissed at me for stealing your car?
因为你在做好事
It was a nice thing to do.
我自己都不确定
I'm not sure
在德语中"好事"到底是指什么
About the German-English translation of nice.
你说偷车是好事  还是
You mean the stealing was nice or...
还是毁了自由战士的一生是好事呢
Ruining Freedom Master's life?
你所做的并非本意
What you did was misguided
而且不负责任
And irresponsible,
但还是好的
But it was also nice.
你给了他享受到真正的幸福
You gave him a moment of pure happiness.
你问我为什么经常来看安妮
You asked me why I come here so often to visit Annie.
她曾是我最好的朋友
She was my best friend.
然后她开始将所有人都拒之门外
Then she started pulling away...from everybody.
医生不知道为什么
The doctors don't know why.
我觉得
I think
嫁给她哥哥是因为
I married her brother because...
他是唯一一个
He was the only other one
与我感同身受的人
Who was going through the same thing.
可他从几年前开始就不再来看她
But he stopped visiting after a couple of years.
我就是
I just...
停不下来
Couldn't stop.
我想她
I miss her.
我该走了
I should go.
晚安
Good night.
发生了什么事
So what happened?
-你愿意理我啦  -才没
- You're talking to me now. - No.
好玩吗
Was it fun?
好玩
Yeah
她吻我了
She kissed me.
不是打比方
Don't read into the phrasing.
我们的确接吻了
We kissed each other.
你觉得如何
And how do you feel about that?
我觉得如何  就是个吻而已
How do I feel about that? It was a kiss.
亲吻总是好事
Kisses are good things.
好的
Okay.
你这话有些弦外之音啊
That was a loaded "okay."
完全没有  你为什么这么说
Not at all. Why would you assume that?
因为你审判我了
Cause you're being judgmental.
如果我说  我昨晚上的智利鲈鱼非常好吃
If I had said that I'd had some delicious chilean sea bass for dinner last night,
你会说  你有何感觉吗
Would you say, "and how do you feel about that?"
如果入锅是鲈鱼有夫之妇  我可能会问
If the sea bass was married, I might.
看吧  你开始说三道四了
See, you're being judgmental.
是不是违反了你的什么原则
Isn't that against your code or something?
我只是陈述事实而已
I'm simply stating the obvious.
事情很复杂
It's complicated,
不仅是因为她是有夫之妇
Not just because she's married
也不仅是因为你被关在精神病院
And not just because you're institutionalized.
你已经花了十二个小时
I know you spent the last 12 hours
想要弄明白那个吻的意义
Trying to figure out what that kiss means.
那天停车场的那个女人是谁
Who's that woman you were with in the parking lot?
你转移话题时
When you deflect,
比你坦言时更能表达自己的感受
It's more effective when you're not that transparent.
出轨对你而言再平常不过
Obviously you have no problem with the infidelity.
你只是在给自己辩护
You're trying to rationalize that,
如果你这医生可以这样  我也可以
"If it's okay for your doctor, it's okay."
但事先声明
But just for the record,
-我没有婚外恋  -那她是谁
- I am not having an affair. - Then who is she?
什么让如此费尽心机地
Why do you think you're working so hard
挖掘我的私生活
To figure out the details of my personal life?
我也许大可不必大费周章
I might not have to work so hard
如果这里的人还有隐私可以的话
If there were some personal items in here.
你只有一个速拨号码
You got one number on speed dial.
名称是"爸爸"
It says "dad."
拜托  你都多大了
Come on, how old are you?
为什么你害怕提及这个话题
Why are you so afraid to talk about this?
我只想说说你
I want to talk about you.
我想知道是谁在给我忠告
I want to know who I'm taking advice from.
我并没有给你忠告  我只是在问你问题
I'm not giving you advice. I'm asking you questions.
那一吻意味深长
I think that kiss meant a lot.
这一吻让你害怕了
I think that scares you.
我没有掺杂私人因素
I think there are no personal items in here
因为你压根就没有私生活
Because you have no personal life.
你觉得你和利迪娅结局会如何
How do you think you and Lydia will end?
你这个寂寞的老男人
You are a lonely man.
你错过生命中所有的姻缘
You've screwed up every opportunity you've had in life.
你们会如何结束呢
What's the ending to the story?
我不知道
I don't know.
探访时间
Visiting time!
你为什么亲我呢
Why did you kiss me?
要有多少个理由呢
How many reasons are there?
我喜欢你
I like you.
我觉得这是个示爱的好方式
It felt like a nice way of showing you that.
"童年情景"  苏珊娜
"Kinderszenen" opus. 15 -- Susanna
把门扶好
Open it all the way. Keep it open.
跟利迪娅怎样了
How'd it go with Lydia?
我俩会一直快活逍遥
I found out you can only be happy so long
直到那个断腿的疯子被人从电梯推出来
Before the catatonic guy with two broken limbs rolls off the elevator,
打比方而已
Philosophically speaking.
为什么你的眼里就只有失败呢
Why do you value your failures more than your successes?
我对着外婆照片手淫时被我妈逮个正着
My mother caught me masturbating to pictures of her mother
我们能不能别再玩这些隐喻了
Can we get past these cute deflections?
无论多成功  半路总会杀出个程咬金
Successes only last until someone screws them up.
失败是永远的
Failures are forever.
于是你接受事实
So you accept that fact.
如果接受事实  你无能为力
You accept that there's nothing you can do.
行  我接受事实  我无能为力
Okay, I accept the fact that there's nothing I can do.
现在要我怎么办
Now, what can I do?
承认自己的失败
You acknowledge failure,
向前看
And you move past it.
去道歉
You apologize.
道歉是多么强大有力的东西
Powerful things these apologies.
让一个人激动的跳楼
Get someone to jump off a building.
然后跟他说对不起  就继续过自己的日子
You say two words, and you move on with your life.
真是公平合理
Hardly seems fair.
这就是症结所在吗
Is that the issue?
你让他痛苦
You caused him pain.
如果世界是公正的  你会忍受同样的痛苦吗
If the world is just, you have to suffer equally?
你不是上帝  豪斯
You're not god, House.
你只是做错事
You're just another screwed-up human being
而需要继续前进的人
Who needs to move on.
向他道歉
Apologize to him.
让你自己感觉好点
Let yourself feel better.
然后你就能学会让自己
Then you can learn to let yourself...
一直感觉良好
Keep feeling better.
嗨
Hey.
豪斯医生  还好吧
Dr. House, everything okay?
是的
Yeah.
集体活动时间
Time for group.
集体活动时间到了
Group time, everybody!
我有个小惊喜
I have a surprise.
两个星期后的今天
Two weeks from today,
我们会举办梅菲尔德才艺表演
We're going to have the Mayfield talent show.
才艺表演  谁要参加
Talent show? Who's in it?
我非常希望大家都参与
I'd really love it if everybody here could participate.
那么谁来当观众
Then who's gonna watch?
工作人员会来
The staff will come,
亲戚朋友也会来
Friends and family.
你会录下来吗
You gonna tape this?
不会  这是属于我们的
No, it's just for us.
如果只是我们自娱自乐  我反对
Well, if it's just for us, I vote we don't do it.
把它当作我们的快乐治疗法吧
Think of it as a fun way to work on on our therapeutic issues.
阿瓦  也许你可以唱首你的歌
Alvie, maybe you could sing one of your songs.
我不唱歌  我只说唱
I don't sing. I rap.
那好吧  你可以写点关于我们的东西
Okay, well, you can write something just for us.
我不写  我只会即兴创作
I don't write. I just do, freestyle style.
我觉得你已经蠢蠢欲动了
I think you're gonna want to be prepared.
-给我们带来不同寻常的秀吧  -我生来就不同寻常
- Make something special. - Always special.
你呢  黛安
How about you, Diane?
你有什么想要表演的吗
Is there something you'd like to do?
我一点天赋都没有
I don't have any talents.
你当然有
Sure you do.
你们都有
You all do.
史蒂夫  你觉得黛安是不是有
Steve, don't you think that Diane has hidden talent
潜在的天分没被挖掘呢
That we'd all like to see come out?
你真的觉得他会答应吗
You really think he's gonna answer?
终究会的
Eventually.
为什么
Why?
因为事情会过去的
Because things pass.
事过境迁
Things change.
不意味着他们会好起来
It doesn't mean they get better.
你要努力让事情好起来
You got to make things better.
单凭一张嘴不能改变什么
You can't just keep talking and hope for the best.
黛安  你可以和我一起表演
Diane, maybe you and I can work together and figure something out.
我可以救他
I can save him.
"他们偷走了她音乐盒"  他之前是这么说的
"They stole her voice box"  that's what he said.
那是她盯着看的东西
That's what she was staring at.
那是她盯着看的原因
That's why he's staring.
豪斯医生  求你了
Dr. House, please.
因为那有个音乐盒
Cause there's a music box in there.
保安
Orderly.
把它给我  我可以
Come on, just give it to me. I can
我不是在发神经
I am not having a psychotic break.
我保证会管用的
I promise you this will work.
架子顶上那个蓝盒子
It's the blue box there on the top shelf.
这就是你想要的
This is what you wanted.
这就是你要的音乐
This is what you needed  a voice.
你以为自己能用拯救那个不说话的女孩
You thought you could cure silent girl with this.
按照你的理论  也能拯救你
So by your own rationale, it should cure you.
你没有任何问题
There's nothing wrong with you.
你的所有机能都在复原
You're healing. All the parts work.
说话啊
Just speak.
快点  说话  开口说话啊
Come on, speak! Say something!
还是休息一会吧
I think maybe everyone should take a break now.
你是在补救  而非克服它
You're trying to fix instead of moving on
我带来德沃夏克的曲谱
I brought dvorak
四手联弹
Four hands.
怎么了
What?
我要知道这是什么
I need to know what this is.
这是乐谱
It's sheet music.
我跟你说过  这只是
I told you. It's just...
两人之间的快乐
Two people having fun.
一般会有两种结果
There's two possible outcomes.
要么是结束了  有人受伤
It ends. Someone gets hurt.
要么是不了了之  还是有人受伤
Or it doesn't end. Someone gets hurt.
结果虽然很苦
So the end sucks.
但那不意味着开始也很苦
It doesn't mean the beginning has to.
万事皆有终结  生命也有尽头
Everything ends. Life ends.
可那并不意味着我们不能享受生活
It it doesn't mean that we can't enjoy it.
我做不到
I can't, I can't do this.
我只知道  五分钟之前我很开心
All I know is, I was happy five minutes ago,
现在我不是
And now I'm not.
这又有何好处呢
How's that better?
再见了  利迪娅
Good-bye, Lydia.
我真的很担心电惊厥疗法
I'm really worried about E.C.T.
担心是正常的
Apprehension's normal.
还有别人有相同的感觉吗
Has anyone else had it?
他们电过我
They shocked me, man.
谢谢  真是很宽慰
Thanks. That's very reassuring.
我不知道我该不该做
I don't know if I should do it.
要么接受治疗  要么就给我闭嘴
Oh, just do the treatment or shut up.
格雷戈  这是个必经的过程
Greg, there's a process.
那是  一过程
Yes, a process.
不想让别人预知结果而影响过程
Wouldn't want to disrupt the process with results.
西斯昨晚睡得不好
Heezy had a rough night last night.
我猜他想做回混蛋
Guess he decided to go back to being an ass
而不是伪君子了
Instead of a hypocrite.
我们继续
let's move on.
阿瓦  你的说唱词写到哪里了呢
Alvie, are you making any progress writing your rap?
有写
Yeah.
其实  没有
But really, no.
我只是不想把我的歌写下来
I just don't want to write my songs down.
它们都是即兴创作的
It takes all the spontaneity out of it.
不是任何时候的感受
It's not of the moment.
阿瓦  你要是把词写下来
Alvie, if you write things down
当时机来临  轮到我出手
When the time comes my run comes
当我光芒四射
When my spotlight shines
没错  你真是个天才
Yeah, you're a genius.
用"阴茎"来押韵
Rhymes with "penius."
抱歉打扰了  比斯利医生
Sorry to interrupt, Dr. Beasley.
诺兰医生让我给你这个
Dr. Nolan asked me to give you this.
一日外出的许可证
Is this a day pass?
他想见你
He'd like to see you.
谢谢你能来
Thanks for coming.
我希望你能看一下我父亲的病例
I was hoping you could, uh, take a look at my dad's chart.
咨询我吗
A consult?
怎么了
What happened
镇上所有神智正常的医生看遍了吗
You went through every sane doctor in town?
我想你应该很想出来走走
I thought you wouldn't mind getting off the ward.
清洁工是在厨房地板上发现他
Cleaning lady found him on the kitchen floor.
这里的医生认为他不行了
Doctors here don't think that he'll recover,
认为我应该放弃
That I should pull the plug.
我想要补充意见  所以我
I want a second opinion, so I
我想如果不请教你就太浪费了
I thought I'd be a fool not to call you.
腔隙性梗塞
Lacunar infarct,
转为出血性中风
Converted to hemorrhagic stroke.
挤压着他的大脑
It squashed his brain.
他们没遗漏什么
They didn't miss anything.
跟我想的一样
That's what I thought.
跟你知道的一样
That's what you knew.
他的大脑中积满血液
His brain has been replaced by blood.
没救了
It's over.
任何看过片子的医生会做此结论
And that's obvious to any doctor
甚至连精神科医生也会
Who looks at that scan, even a shrink.
你只是想让你点醒你
You want someone to tell you
告诉你放弃治疗是明智之举
That what you need to do is okay,
让别人认可你  赦免你
To give you permission, absolution.
现在不是时候  豪斯
Not now, House.
你没有朋友  没有家人
You have no friends, no family.
在什么时候
At some point,
你犯了错
You made a mistake.
失去了一切
You lost everything.
此刻正好可以用上我这家伙
And now I'm the closest thing you got to a friend.
别说了
Just shut up.
我不需要你来对我冷嘲热讽
I don't need you here to play this game.
很抱歉拒你于千里之外
I'm sorry I pushed you away.
我害怕的时候就会这样
It's what I do when I'm afraid.
重申  德译英或许意思会有偏差
Again, German-English translation may be a little off.
我不是为你而哭
I'm not I'm not crying because of you.
我哭是因为我可悲
I'm crying because I'm pathetic.
我给她带来大提琴
I brought her cello,
为了她能奇迹般苏醒继续上台演出
In case she magically wakes up for the show.
原来如此  那我收我的道歉
Oh, well, then I take the apology back.
我们都是可悲的人
We're all pathetic.
这就是让一切有趣的秘密
It's why makes everything interesting.
我受够了有趣的生活
I'm sick of life being interesting.
女士们  先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
有请独一无二的
The one, the only,
胡安·阿瓦
Juan Alvarez!
唷  唷  怎样
Yo, yo, what's up?
让第六区沸腾起来  大家一起
Ward six is jumping off, y'all!
给DJ里克特点掌声
Give it up for DJ Richter on the ones and twos.
嘿  DJ里克特  我们转起来
Yo, DJ Richter, spin that!
跟上我的感觉  来到这漫长的一天
Welcome to me feel with the day feels long
我们看着挺壮  其实都有点故障
We act strong but that's got to be somethings wrong
你看出他的天资
You got his talents.
却看不出她的隐私
You don't see her secrets.
若给你指明方向
If we can show your goals
那么我们就此生无憾
Then we wouldn't have no regrets.
想知道我的秘密  那让我说给你听
Wannna know my screts so back let me explain it
老爸老妈得病是因为我不学无术
Pa & Ma get sick because I doesn't aim it
那西班牙佬想让我走红
The man in Spain try to make it work
但大夫说我太懒
But the doctor says I'm lazy.
还有我室友是个混球
And my roommate is a jerk.
豪斯医生就在这里
Dr. House is in the House, y'all.
给点掌声  让豪斯医生走上这里
Give it to Dr. House to the stage, y'all.
Putting Dr. House to the stage, y'all.
想听豪斯医生唱歌吗
Are you hear Dr. House's song?
他正迈向舞台
Oh, y, he is coming to the stage, y'all.
是那个豪斯医生吗  我的室友
Is that the Dr. House, my roommate？
豪斯医生是我的室友
Dr. House is my roommate.
他们说吃了药就能好起来
They say they take the pills, they say they make it free.
它们真让你好起来吗
And how does it make you feel better?
晚上睡不着又怎样好呢
If I can't get no sleep?
你上台前  就有一肚子话
You gotta thing before you act
你知道这只是过程
You know it is a progress
当你生活乱套  就顺其自然咯
You don't make an action when your whole life is a mass
医生快告诉我该知道些什么
So tell me doctor I really got to know
怎么能变好
How to make me better?
就来才艺表演吧
Just do a talent show
我猜那就是个灾难
And when I guess it's just a mass,
那是  你刚说的  兄弟
Yes, you just tell me, brother
我们的生活就是如此不堪
Our life is restlessness
至少我们拥有彼此
Unless we have each other
我们拥有彼此
Oh, we got each other.
Oh, we got each other...
就像血浓于水的亲兄弟
Like two brother have one mother，
叫你家老妈来看哦
Told you mother come on watch this
你怎么样了
How are you doing?
还硬撑着吗
You hanging in there?
这通常是我的开场白
Usually I open with that.
谢谢你陪着我
Thanks for staying.
那
So, um...
你想谈什么
What do you want to talk about?
事情其实
Things are actually...
很顺利
Actually good.
好吧  你这么说该不会是
Okay, you're not you're not just saying that
因为你不想
Because you don't want to complain
在一个承受丧父之痛的人面前抱怨吧
In front of the guy who just lost his father?
我人没好到那种程度
I'm not that cured.
我还得做点什么  但是
No, I still got stuff to do, but...
我很好
I'm good.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我一心想证明自己是对的
I was trying to prove a point.
我一心想做对的事
I was trying to be right.
却把你置身于危险之中
I ended up putting you in a dangerous situation,
而我自己却无力应对
And I was not equipped to handle it.
你受了伤
You got hurt,
都是我的错
And it's my fault.
我很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
吃药时间
Med time
今天我要吃那些粉红色药片  你呢
I'm gonna try those pink ones today. You?
谢谢你
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
给你一个惊喜
Got a surprise.
今天  我们在此祝贺
Today we're here to congratulate...
安妮
Annie!
我们为你骄傲
We're proud of her!
我们祝她一路走好  祝她
We wish her well, and we hope
一去不复返
To never see her again!
如果你沉默了二十多年
If you go silent for over a decade,
是不能一下子就回归社会
You don't just get to slide right back into society.
她会先去在亚利桑那州疗养院
She's going to a rehab facility first in Arizona.
她的家人要搬去那里
Her family's moving there.
抱歉  豪斯
Sorry, House.
我也是刚刚得知的
I just found out myself.
我要一个外出过夜许可
I want an overnight pass.
我可以帮你
I can help you with this.
-那是我应得的  -那是  但
- I've earned it. - You have, but
信任我不正是治愈计划的一部分吗
Isn't extending trust part of the whole "getting me better" thing?
如果你坚持要许可  我可以给你
If you insist on a pass, I'll give it to you.
我知道你要去哪
But I know where you're going,
而且我知道你是一时冲动
And I know you haven't thought it through.
我们应该坐下来  好好谈谈
We need to sit down, talk about this.
给我外出许可
Please give me the pass.
嗨
Hi.
你好
Hello.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是
I'm
本  进屋里去  好吗
Ben, go inside, okay?
你就这么不辞而别吗
You didn't say anything.
安妮要走了
And now Annie's leaving,
我听说你要去亚利桑那州
And I hear you're going to Arizona.
我丈夫经常去凤凰城
My husband travels to Phoenix a lot.
他公司的总部在那
His corporate headquarters are there,
这么多年来我们一直想搬过去
And we've been wanting to move for years,
但是我们被拴在这里
But we've been tethered here.
现在我们解放了
And now we're not.
我不想让你走
I don't want you to go.
我也不想走
I don't want to go.
但我不能拆散我的家庭
But I can't break up my family.
我不能抛下我的孩子
I-I can't leave my children.
你不想改变现状
So you don't want it to change.
很抱歉  我这么不辞而别
I'm sorry and I didn't come to say goodbye.
我想让这份美好的感觉留在心底
I thought it was kind of prefect
我得走了
I have to go.
你的许可证用得不是很开心
Not the most exciting use of the overnight pass I've ever seen.
她走了
She left.
还有就是
And...
我不知所措了
I'm lost.
我会为你写推荐信给医委会
I'm gonna write your letter to the medical board,
让他们返还你的行医执照
Recommending that they give your license back.
你不能这样哄我
You can't just console me
就像给摔跤的孩子棒棒糖吃
By giving me a lollipop when I skin my knee.
好吧  刚刚发生了两件事
Well, two things just happened.
你受了伤
You got hurt,
说明你和他人有所深交
Which means you connected to someone else,
并且深深地思念他们
Strongly enough to miss them.
更重要的是
And more important...
你意识到心灵的痛  并且找我倾诉
You recognized the pain and came to talk to me,
而非把痛苦藏在维科丁药瓶里
Instead of hiding from it in the vicodin bottle.
你做到了  你受伤了  你来到这里
The fact that you're hurting and you came here,
你吃下给你开的药
The fact that you're taking your meds
我们正在敞开心扉
And we're talking right now...
进去睡觉吧
Come inside and get some sleep.
明天你就可以走了
Tomorrow you can start saying your good-byes.
今天  我们在此祝贺格雷戈
Today we're here to congratulate Greg.
我们为他骄傲
We're proud of him.
我们祝他一路走好  祝他
We wish her well, and we hope
一去不复返
To never see her again!
豪斯
House!
走开
Back off.
大家已经觉得我们是同性恋了
People already think we're gay.
你想要什么  阿瓦
What do you need, Alvie?
我的药
My meds.
我想要好起来
I want to get better.